[Music]
today
i felt the need to calm my racing mind
sometimes i try to sit and take deep
breaths or watch a lighthearted movie
but today i woke up and i knew that some
healthy escapism was in order in the
form of some good books
i also decided to let you guys in on my
best kept secret
and that is that all spare cupboard
space in my kitchen is used for storing
my many books
i decided today it was high time to
confess to my potential future identity
as a book hoarder
and do some reorganizing
[Music]
so
hey
tickles
[Music]
so
one of my favorite movies is called
finding neverland
it's a story about the author of peter
pan
you may be familiar with the story of
peter already it's about a magical boy
who takes an
ordinary girl named wendy and her two
brothers to a fantastical place called
neverland
where children can be young forever in
this world
everyone can fly if they're sprinkled
with pixie dust
i had the pleasure of studying the book
when i was a university student
in the story there are a group of lost
boys who spend their time in neverland
going on adventures
the part of the story that you may not
know if you haven't read the book
is that the lost boys chose to come home
with wendy when she returns to the real
world
after a while the lost boys regret
leaving neverland
and at night their dreams would take
them back to that wondrous place
to keep them from flying off in their
sleep they had to be tied down to the
bed
over time as they grew into adults they
stopped trying to fly
and forgot about neverland altogether in
many ways the author of peter pan may
have wanted us to take a lesson from the
characters in this story
he sums it up in his favorite quote the
moment you doubt whether or not you can
fly
you can no longer do it
i believe the characters show us how
dangerous it is to get so wrapped up in
the real world
that you forget to exercise your
imagination or wonder not how things are
but how they could be to be able to
envision the world you would like to
live in
and be the change you want to see
instead of believing there's no point to
thinking that way
to spend time dreaming and enjoying all
the forms of art that stretch your mind
anything from books to movies and music
for me i personally find that reading
stories
inspires me to continue to have a
hopeful and positive outlook
if you saw my last video you know we
endured a heat wave and after it came
many wildfires in my area
and shortly after i filmed this video
the sky is filled with
so much smoke that i was no longer able
to see my beloved mountains in the
distance
the cascades have been blocked out for
days now and understandably it filled me
with worry
[Music]
in strange times such as these i noticed
that there are different approaches to
uncertainty about the future
one that i find inspiring is people who
take action and make practical steps
towards improving their world
another can be more defeatist that the
future isn't something to look forward
to
or try to change i choose to take an
approach directly inspired by the
message and the story of peter pan
if i choose to lose hope i will no
longer be able to see it
i will forget about the importance of
dreaming and believing in a better
tomorrow
and letting stories and art and
imagination help me visualize it
i love my home i believe in the world
full of love and that that is what hope
has always been
the act of loving
[Music]
do
i've included some of my favorite books
movies and music in the description bar
i thought i'd take a very self-indulgent
minute to show you some of the more
unusual books in my collection
one is this thrifted and stunning copy
of dunn's poetry
and my most treasured book is this
collection of british poetry
that i found at a thrift store and was
signed and annotated by a man named alan
who owned it in 1912 and i found it in
2014.
as a lover of history i love collecting
antique books
another favorite is the diary of the
edwardian lady
i also admit that i have quite a few
books that i own because the art
inspired me to paint
and i have no idea what most of them are
about i'll get around to reading them
someday
do
[Music]
so
do
i also have a few treasured books from
my childhood
including this very worn copy of flower
fairy art
thank you for indulging my love of
reading today
let me know what your favorite book
movie or music
is wishing you a lovely day or night
take
that's care
[Music]
you